<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "beaker_user_guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-beaker_user_guide-Provision">
<title>Provisioning a System</title>

		<para>
			If you would like to use one of these System you will need to provision it. There are a couple of ways of doing this, which are outlined below
		</para>
		<section id="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-System_Provisioning-Provision_by_System">
			<title>Provision by System</title>
			<para>
				Go to the System details page (see <xref linkend="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-System_Details" />) of a System that is free (see <xref linkend="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-System_Searching" />) and click on <literal>Take</literal> in the <literal>Current User</literal> field. After succesfully taking the System, click the <literal>Provision</literal> tab of the System details page to provision the System.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/system_provision_by_system.png" format="PNG" width="444" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</section>
		
		<section id="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-System_Provisioning-Provision_by_Distro">
			<title>Provision by Distro</title>
			<para>
				Go to the Distro search page(<xref linkend="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Distros-Distro_Searching" />) and search for a Distro you would like to provision onto a System. Once you have found the Distro you require, click <literal>Provision System</literal>, which is located in the far right column of your search results. If the <literal>Provision System</literal> link is not there, it's because there is no suitable System available to use with that Distro.
			</para>
			<para>
				The resulting page lists the Systems you can use. Systems with <literal>Reserve Now</literal> in the far right column mean that no on else is using them and you can take them immedietly, otherwise you will see <literal>Queue Reservation</literal>; which means that someone is currently using the System but you can be appended to the queue of people wanting to use this System.
			</para>
			<para>
				After choosing your System and clicking on the the aforementioned links, you will be presented with a form with the following fields 
				<variablelist>
					<varlistentry><term>System To Provision</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								This is our System we will provision.
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry><term>Distro To Provision</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								The Distro we will be installing on the System.
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry><term>Job Whiteboard</term>
		
						<listitem>
							<para>
								This is a refernce that will be displayed in Jobs list. You can enter anything in here.
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry><term>KickStartMetaData</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								Arguments passed to the KickStart script.<remark>Is this right</remark>?
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry><term>Kernel Options (install)</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<remark>Not sure what goes here</remark>	
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					<varlistentry><term>Kernel Options(Post)</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<remark>Not sure what goes here</remark>	
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
				 Pressing the <literal>Queue Job</literal> button will submit this provisioning as a Job and redirect us to the details of the newly created Job.
			</para>
		</section>
</chapter>
