<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "beaker_user_guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="chap-beaker_user_guide-Components-Reports">
	<title>Reports</title>
	<para>
        Beaker offers a few different reports. They can be accessed from the <literal>Reports</literal> menu at the top of the page.
        The <literal>Reserve</literal> report will give reservation details of Systems that are currently in use. The other report offered is the <literal>Matrix</literal> report.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-beaker_user_guide-Reports-Matrix_Report">
		<title>Matrix Report</title>
		<para>
                The <literal>Matrix</literal> report gives a user an overall picture of results for any given Job, or number of Jobs combined. It shows a matrix of
                Tasks run and the Arch that they were run on. The <literal>Reports-&gt;Matrix</literal> is accesable from the top menu.		
		</para>
		<figure><title>Generating a Matrix report from the Job's Whiteboard</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/report_matrix.png" format="PNG" width="444" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
               
                <para>
                There are two ways of defining what Job results to display. You can select the Job by its <literal>Whiteboard</literal>, or by its <literal>Job ID</literal>. 
                To show a Job's Matrix report from its Whiteboard, click on the Whiteboard text in the <literal>Whiteboard</literal> select box. 
                If you wish to select the Job by its ID, enter the Job ID into the <literal>Job ID</literal> text area. The Job Whiteboard and the Job ID are mutually 
                exclusive when generating the Matrix report. To change between the two, click on their respective input areas.  Click the <literal>Generate</literal> button to
                create the report. 
                <note><title>Filtering Whiteboards</title> <para>You can filter what is displayed in the <literal>Whiteboard</literal> select box by typing text 
                 into the <literal>Filter Whiteboard</literal> field, and then clicking anywhere outside the field.</para>
                 </note>
                 <note><title>Displaying reports of any combination of Jobs</title> <para>Displaying the Matrix reports of any Jobs together, is possible when selecting
                  by <literal>Job ID</literal>. Enter in all the relevant <literal>Job IDs</literal> seperate by whitespace or a newline.</para>
                 </note>
                </para> 
		<figure><title>Generating a Matrix report from the Job ID</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/report_matrix_generate.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
                <para>
                The generated Matrix report shows the result of each Task with its corresponding Arch and Recipe Whiteboard. The points in the matrix describe the result of the 
                Task, and how many occurences of that result there are. Clicking on these results will take you to the <literal>Executed Tasks</literal> page. 
                See <xref linkend="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Tasks-Task_Searching" />.
                </para>
		<figure><title>Viewing the result of one or more Jobs via the Matrix report</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/report_matrix_results.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
               
                

	</section>

</section>

