<section id="chap-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems">
	<title>Systems</title>
	<para>
		Beaker provides an inventory of Systems(These could be a physical machine,laptop,virtual guest, or resource) attached to lab controllers. Systems can be added, removed, have details changed, and be provisioned amongst other things.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-System_Searching">
		<title>System Searching</title>
		<para>
			System searches are conducted by clicking on one of the items of the <guimenu>System</guimenu> menu at the top of the page. 
			<variablelist><title>System Searches</title>
                        	<varlistentry><term>All</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Will search through all Systems listed in Beaker.
						</para>
					</listitem>
                        	 </varlistentry>
                                <varlistentry><term>Available</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							 Will search through only Systems that the currently logged in user has permission to reserve.
						</para>
					</listitem>
                                </varlistentry>
                                <varlistentry><term>Free</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Will search through only Systems that the currently logged in user has permission to reserve and are currently free.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
                         </variablelist>
		
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/system_menu.png" format="PNG" width="444" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
		<para>
			The search panel has two modes; simple and advanced. The simple search is the default, and the default search is of the System <literal>Name</literal>, using the <literal>contains</literal> operator. To toggle between the two search modes, press the <literal>Toggle Search</literal> link.
		</para>
		<para id="advanced_search">
			The advanced search panel is reasonably self explanatory. The first column(<literal>Table</literal>) is the attribute on which the search is being performed, the second(<literal>Operation</literal>) is the type of search, and the third(<literal>Value</literal>) is the actual value to search on.
                        The operators change depending on what type of attribute is being searched. 
			<note>
				<title>Wildcards</title>
				<para>
					No operator provides explicit wildcards other than the <literal>is</literal> operation, which allows the <literal>*</literal> wildcard when searching an attribute which is a string.
				</para>
			</note>
		</para>
		<para>
			The kind of data returned in the System search can be changed by adding/removing the result columns. To do this the <literal>Toggle Result Columns</literal> link is pressed and the columns checked/unchecked.
		</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="./images/system_search_panel.png" format="PNG" width="444" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>
			<note>
				<title>Shortcut for finding Systems you are using</title>
				<para>
					The top right hand corner has a menu which srarts with <literal>Hello,</literal> followed by the name of the user currently logged in. Click on this, then down to <literal>My Systems</literal>
				</para>
			</note>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-Adding_a_System">
		<title>Adding a System</title>
		<para>
			To add a System, go to any System search page, and click on the <literal>Add(+)</literal> link on the bottom left. You must be logged in to do this. After filling in the details, press the <literal>Save Changes</literal> button on the bottom left hand corner.
		</para>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="./images/system_add.png" format="PNG" width="444" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-System_Details">
		<title>System Details Tabs</title>
		<para>
			After finding a System in the search page, clicking on the System name will show the System details. To change these details, you must be logged in as either the owner of the System, or an admin.
		</para>
		<para>	
			<variablelist><title>System Details</title>
				<varlistentry><term>Details</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Shows the details of the System's CPU, as well as Devices attached to the System.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Arch</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Shows the architects supported by the system.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Key/Values</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Shows further hardware details.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Groups</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Shows the groups of which this System is a part of.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Excluded Families</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
						 	Are the list of Distros that this System does not support.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			
				<varlistentry><term>Power</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Allows the powering off/on and rebooting of this System. These options are only available if you are the current user of this System or in the admin group.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Notes</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Any info about the system that you want others to see and doesn't fit in anywhere else.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Install Options</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<remark>Need Info</remark>	
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>

				<varlistentry><term>Provision</term>	
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Allows the user of this System to install a Distro on it.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Lab Info</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Will display practical details of the System like cost, power usage, weight etc.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>History</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Shows the activity on this System for the duration of the systems life as an inventory item in Beaker. These activites can also be searched. By default, the simple search does a <literal>contains</literal> search on the <literal>Field</literal> attribute. Please see <xref linkend="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-System_Searching"/> for details on searching.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-System_Activity">
		<title>System Activity</title>
		<para>
			To search through the historical activity of all Systems, navigate to <guimenu>Activity</guimenu>&gt;<guimenuitem>All</guimenuitem> at the top of the page. The default search is <literal>contains</literal> on the <literal>Property</literal> attribute. 
			<note>
				<title>Individual System history</title>
				<para>
					To search the history of a specific System, see the <literal>History</literal> tab in <xref linkend="sect-beaker_user_guide-Components-Systems-System_Details" />
				</para>
			</note>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/system_activity_all.png" format="PNG" width="444" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</para>
	</section>
</section>

