<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

                  <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile">
                      <title>Beaker Makefile</title>
                        <para>This guide provide in depth information for the required and optional Makefile variables in an Beaker test. A sample Makefile is copied into the local directory when rhts-create-new-test tool is invoked (or can be found at    <command>/usr/share/doc/beaker-devel-x.y/Makefile.template </command>).</para>
                          <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-Package_Name">
                            <title>PACKAGE NAME</title>
                          <screen># The name of the package under test:
    PACKAGE_NAME=gcc
                          </screen>
                          <para>
                          The package under test is the common command or executable being tested. This must be the name of an installable RPM in the distribution. If the focus of your test is a third party application, set PACKAGE_NAME equal to the primary package used by the third party application. For example, if you are writing a Beaker test to test a web application based on CGI, set PACKAGE_NAME to perl.
                          </para>
                        </section>
                        <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-TOPLEVEL_NAMESPACE">
                          <title>TOPLEVEL NAMESPACE</title>
                          <screen># The toplevel namespace within which the test lives.
    TOPLEVEL_NAMESPACE=CoreOS
                          </screen>
                        <para>The <application>Makefile</application> contains three hierarchies resembling file systems, each with their own collections of paths. In order to ensure consistency between test creators and tests, the provided <application>Makefile</application> should be used to manage these hierarchies. Thus, the scheme in the <application>Makefile</application> template does all the work. 
                        </para>
                        <para>For clarity, it is worth noting the hierarchies at this time:
                          <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                              <para>
                                <emphasis>installation</emphasis> tests are built as packages for clean deployment on test machines. More than one test can be run on a given machine, so there is a hierarchy below /mnt/tests which keeps the files of the individual tests separate from each other. This is set in each test's Makefile.  
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                              <para>
                                <emphasis>result namespace</emphasis> a hierarchical namespace for results. For example, tests relating to the kernel report their results somewhere within the /kernel subtree, and tests relating to the NFS file system (as a part of the kernel) report their results inside /kernel/filesystems/nfs/. Each test "owns" a subtree of the namespace, specified by the Name: field of the metadata. Many tests report only a single result, but it is possible for a test to write out a complex hierarchy of results below its subtree. 
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                          </itemizedlist>
                        </para>
                        <para>The following top level reporting namespaces are predefined and should used to ensure consistent reporting of test results. These are the only valid accepted namespaces.
                          <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                              <para><application>distribution</application> contains tests that involve the distribution as a whole, or a large number of packages, for example<application> /distribution/standards/posixtestsuite</application> 
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                              <para><application>kernel</application> contains tests results relating to the kernel, for example <application>/kernel/xen/xm/dmesg</application>
                                <itemizedlist>
                                  <listitem>
                                    <para>The <application>kernel</application> namespace is unique in that it is also the name of a package. In this case it is usually best to define the<application> TOPLEVEL_NAMESPACE</application> like this: 
                                      <screen># The toplevel namespace definition for kernel tests
              TOPLEVEL_NAMESPACE=$(PACKAGE_NAME)
                                      </screen>
                                    </para>
                                  </listitem>
                                </itemizedlist>
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                              <para><application>Desktop</application> contains tests results relating to desktop packages, for example<application> /desktop/evolution/first-time-wizard-password-settings</application>, which is a specific test relating to evolution 
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                              <para><application>Tools</application> contains tests results relating to the tool chain, for example <application>/tools/gcc/testsuite/3.4</application>
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                              <para><application>CoreOS</application> all test results relating to user-space packages not covered by any of the above namespaces 
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                              <para><application>Examples</application> example tests that illustrate usage and functionality and are not activly maintained. This is a good place to experiment when you are getting hang of Beaker or to place simple examples to help others.
                              </para>
                            </listitem>
                          </itemizedlist>
                         </para>
                      </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-RELATIVE_PATH">
                          <title>RELATIVE PATH</title>
                            <screen>
                   # The path of the test below the package:
                     RELATIVE_PATH=example-compilation 
                            </screen>
                            <para>
                            An implementation of Beaker should run the test from the directory containing the <application>runtest.sh</application>, as listed in the <application>RELATIVE_PATH</application> file of the<application> Makefile</application>. If the test needs to move around, store this somewhere with <application>DIR=`pwd`</application> or use <application>pushd</application> and <application>popd</application>. 
                            </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-TESTVERSION">
                          <title>TESTVERSION</title>
                          <screen>
               # Version of the Test. Used with make tag.
                export TESTVERSION=1.0
                          </screen>
                          <para>This is used when building a package of a test, and provides the "version" component of the RPM name-version-release triplet. 
                            <itemizedlist>
                              <listitem>
                                <para>The value must be valid as an RPM version string. 
                                </para>
                              </listitem>
                              <listitem>
                                <para>It may consist of numbers, letters, and the dot symbol.
                                </para>
                              </listitem>
                              <listitem>
                                <para>It may not include a dash symbol this is used by RPM to delimit the version string within the name-version-release triplet. 
                                </para>
                              </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist>
                          </para>
                          <para>When writing a test from scratch, use 0.1 and increment gradually until the test has reached a level of robustness to merit a "1.0" release. When wrapping a test from an upstream location, use the upstream version string here, as closely as possibly given the restrictions on valid characters. The version should be incremented each time a change is made to the <application>Makefile</application> or test files and a RPM is created from these files to be publicly consumed in a test review or submission to a lab scheduler. 
                          </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-TEST">
                          <title>TEST</title>
                          <screen>
                  # The compiled namespace of the test.
                  export TEST=$(TOPLEVEL_NAMESPACE)/$(PACKAGE_NAME)/$(RELATIVE_PATH)
                          </screen>
                          <para>
                          This variable defines the path to a test. This path should also be the same in source control. 
                          </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-BUILT_FILES">
                        <title>BUILT_FILES</title>
                        <screen>BUILT_FILES=hello-world</screen>
                        <para>List the files that need to be compiled to be used in the test.</para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-FILES_METADATA">
                         <title>FILES=$(METADATA)</title>
                         <screen>
           FILES=$(METADATA) runtest.sh Makefile PURPOSE hello-world.c \
                     verify-hello-world-output.sh
                         </screen>
                         <para>List all of the files needed to run the test to insure that there are no packaging errors when the test is built binaries should be pulled in via BUILT_FILES. </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-Targets">
                          <title>Targets</title>
                            <para>Each test must supply a run target which allows an implementation of the framework to invoke <application>make run</application>. It is usually best to have this as the first target defined in the <application>Makefile</application> so that a simple invocation of<application> make</application> will use it as the default, and run the test. Note how the <application>build</application> target is set up as a dependency of run to ensure that this happens if necessary. 
                             </para>
                             <para>Additional targets and variables supplied by the include for<application> /usr/share/beaker/lib/beaker-make.include</application>. This file is supplied with<application> beaker-devel</application> as seen below.
                             </para>
                             <screen>[root@dhcp83-5 example-compilation]# cat /usr/share/rhts/lib/rhts-make.include
# Copyright (c) 2006  All rights reserved. This copyrighted material l
# is made available to anyone wishing to use, modify, copy, or
# redistribute it subject to the terms and conditions of the GNU General
# Public License v.2.
#
# This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT AN Y
# WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A
# PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.
#
# You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
# along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
# Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA.
#
# Author: Your Name &lt;name@company.com&gt;

#
# rhts-make.include
#
# default rules and settings for rhts makefiles
#

# Common Variables.
TEST_DIR=/mnt/tests$(TEST)
INSTALL_DIR=$(DEST)$(TEST_DIR)
METADATA=testinfo.desc

# tag: mark the test source as a release

tag:
        rhts-mk-tag-release

release: tag

# prep: prepare the test(s) for packaging

install: $(FILES) runtest.sh testinfo.desc
        mkdir -p $(INSTALL_DIR)
        cp -a $(FILES) Makefile $(INSTALL_DIR)
        install -m 0755 runtest.sh $(INSTALL_DIR)

# package: build the test package

package:
        rhts-mk-build-package


# submit: submit the test package to RHTS

submit:
        rhts-mk-build-package -s $(TESTSERVER)

##################################################
# example makefile
#
# include ~/devel/rhts/greg/rhts_nb/make.include
#
# FILES=prog1.c prog2.c
#
# ARENA=$(DEST)/mnt/tests/glibc/double-free-exploit
#
# install:
#       mkdir -p $(ARENA)
#       cp -a runtest.sh $(FILES) $(ARENA)
#
# run: tests
#       runtest.sh
#
# tests: prog2 prog2</screen>
                             <para>The <application>tag</application> target is used to tag a package in anticipation of submitting it to a test lab. 
                             </para>
                             <para>The <application>submit</application> target is used to submit a package to a test lab and requires the <application>TESTSERVER</application> variable to be defined. It builds an<application> RPM</application> of the test (if necessary) and uploads the test package to a test lab controller where it can be used to schedule tests. 
                             </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-MATADATA">
                          <title>$(METADATA)</title>
                            <para>Following is an example of the <application>METADATA</application> section needed to execute a basic test. Following subsections will comment briefly on the values that must be set manually (not set by variables) and optional values to enhance test reporting and execution. </para>
                            <screen>$(METADATA): Makefile
    @touch $(METADATA)
    @echo "Owner:        Your Name &lt;name@company.com&gt;" > $(METADATA)
    @echo "Name:         $(TEST)" >> $(METADATA)
    @echo "Path:         $(TEST_DIR)" >> $(METADATA)
    @echo "License:      GPLv2" >> $(METADATA)
    @echo "TestVersion:  $(TESTVERSION)" >> $(METADATA)
    @echo "Description:  Ensure that compiling a simple .c file works as expected" >> $(METADATA)
    @echo "TestTime:     1m" >> $(METADATA)
    @echo "RunFor:       $(PACKAGE_NAME)" >> $(METADATA)  # add any other packages for which your test ought to run here
    @echo "Requires:     $(PACKAGE_NAME)" >> $(METADATA)  # add any other requirements for the script to run here</screen>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-Owner">
                          <title>Owner</title>
                          <para><application>Owner</application>: (optional) is the person responsible for this test. Initially for Beaker, this will be whoever committed the test to Subversion. A naming policy may have to be introduced as the project develops. Acceptable values are a subset of the set of valid email addresses, requiring the form: <application>Owner: human readable name &lt;username@domain&gt;.</application>
                          </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-Name">
                          <title>Name</title>
                          <para><application>Name: </application>(required) It is assumed that any result-reporting framework will organize all available tests into a hierarchical namespace, using forward-slashes to separate names (analogous to a path). This field specifies the namespace where the test will appear in the framework, and serves as a unique ID for the test. Tests should be grouped logically by the package under test. This name should be consistent with the name used in source control too. Since some implementations will want to use the file system to store results, make sure to only use characters that are usable within a file system path. 
                          </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-Description">
                            <title>Description</title>
                            <para><application>Description</application> (required) must contain exactly one string. </para>
                            <para>For example: </para>
                            <screen>Description: This test tries to map five 1-gigabyte files with a single process.
Description: This test tries to exploit the recent security issue for large pix map files.
Description: This test tries to panic the kernel by creating thousands of processes.</screen>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-TestTime">
                          <title>TestTime</title>
                            <para>Every <application>Makefile</application> must contain exactly one<application> TestTime</application> value. It represent the upper limit of time that the <application>runtest.sh</application> script should execute before being terminated. That is, the API should automatically fail the test after this time period has expired. This is to guard against cases where a test has entered an infinite loop or caused a system to hang. This field can be used to achieve better test lab utilization by preventing the test from running on a system indefinitely.    </para>
                            <para>The value of the field should be a number followed by either the letter "m" or "h" to express the time in minutes or hours. It can also be specified it in seconds by giving just a number. It is recommended to provide a value in minutes, for readability.
                            </para>
                            <para>The time should be the absolute longest a test is expected to take on the slowest platform supported, plus a 10% margin of error. It is usually meaningless to have a test time of less than a minute, since some implementations of the API may be attempting to communicate with a busy server such as writing back to an NFS share or performing an XML-RPC call. 
                            </para>
                            <para>For example:</para>
                            <screen>TestTime: 90   # 90 seconds
TestTime: 1m   # 1 minute
TestTime: 2h   # 2 hours</screen>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-Requires">
                          <title>Requires</title>
                            <para><application>Requires</application> one or more. This field indicates the packages that are required to be installed on the test machine for the test to work. The package being tested is automatically included via the<application> PACKAGE_NAME</application> variable. Anything <application>runtest.sh</application> needs for execution must be included here. </para>
                            <para>This field can occur multiple times within the metadata. Each value should be a space-separated list of package names, or of Kickstart package group names preceded with an @ sign. Each package or group must occur within the distribution tree under test (specifically, it must appear in the  <application>comps.xml </application>file).</para>
                            <para>For exmaple:</para>
                              <screen>
@echo "Requires:     gdb" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA) 
@echo "Requires:     @legacy-software-development" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA) 
@echo "Requires:     @kde-software-development" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA) 
@echo "Requires:     -pdksh" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA)</screen>
                              <para>The last example above shows that we don't want a particular package installed for this test. Normally you shouldn't have to do this unless the package is installed by default.</para>
                              <para>In a lab implementation, the dependencies of the packages listed can be automatically loaded using yum.</para>
                              <para>Note that unlike an RPM spec file, the names of packages are used rather than Provides: dependencies. If one of the dependencies changes name between releases, one of these approaches below may be helpful:
                              <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                  <para>for major changes, split the test, so that each release is a separate test in a sub-directory, with the common files built from a shared directory in the <application>Makefile. </application>
                                  </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                  <para>if only a dependency has changed name, specify the union of the names of dependencies in the Requires: field; an implementation should silently ignore unsolvable dependencies. 
                                  </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                  <para>it may be possible to work around the differences by logic in the section of the<application> Makefile</application> that generates the <application>testinfo.desc </application>file.
                                  </para>
                                </listitem>
                              </itemizedlist>
                              </para>
                              <para>When writing a multihost test involving multiple roles client(s) and server(s), the union of the requirements for all of the roles must be listed here. 
                              </para>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-RHTSRequires">
                          <title>RHTSRequires</title>
                            <para><application>RHTSRequires</application> one or more. This field indicates the other beaker tests that are required to be installed on the test machine for the test to work.</para>
                            <para>This field can occur multiple times within the metadata. Each value should be a space-separated list of Beaker Test RPM name without the version or .rpm. Each Test must exist on the Beaker Scheduler.</para>
                            <para>For example: </para>
                            <screen>@echo "RHTSRequires:     rh-tests-distribution-hts-common" >> $(METADATA)</screen>
                         </section>
                         <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-RunFor">
                          <title>RunFor</title>
                            <para><application>RunFor</application> allows for the specification of the packages which are relevant for the test. This field is the hook to be used for locating tests by package. For example, when running all tests relating to a particular package[1], an implementation should use this field. Similarly, when looking for results on a particular package, this is the field that should be used to locate the relevant test runs.    </para>
                            <para>When testing a specific package, that package must be listed in this field. If the test might reasonably be affected by changes to another package, the other package should be listed here. If a package changes name in the various releases of the distribution, all its names should be listed here.    </para>
                            <para>This field is optional; and can occur multiple times within the metadata. The value should be a space-separated list of package names. </para>
                         </section>
                       <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Beaker_Makefile-Releases">
                          <title>Releases</title>
                            <para>Some tests are only applicable to certain distribution releases. For example, a kernel bug may only be applicable to RHEL3 which contains the 2.4 kernel. Limiting the release should only be used when a test will not execute on a particular release. Otherwise, the release should not be restricted so that your test can run on as many different releases as possible.
                               <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Valid <application>Releases</application> arevanything that is a valid Family in Beaker, such as: 
                                       <itemizedlist>
                                           <listitem>
                                               <para>RedHatEnterpriseLinux3 
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>RedHatEnterpriseLinux4 
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                               <para>RedHatEnterpriseLinuxServer5 
                                               </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                               <para>RedHatEnterpriseLinuxClient5 
                                               </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                               <para>FedoraCore6 
                                               </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                               <para>Fedora7 
                                               </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                               <para>Fedora8 
                                               </para>
                                             </listitem>
                                          </itemizedlist>
                                       </para>
                          </listitem>
                          <listitem>
                              <para>Releases can be used in two ways: 
                                 <itemizedlist>
                                  <listitem>
                                    <para>specifying releases you <application>want</application> run your test for : For example, if you want to run your test on RHEL3 and RHEL4 only, add "Releases: RedHatEnterpriseLinux3 RedHatEnterpriseLinux4" to your Makefile METADATA variable, i.e.: 
                                    <screen>
...
@echo "Requires:        openldap-servers" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA)
@echo "Releases:        RedHatEnterpriseLinux3 RedHatEnterpriseLinux4" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA)
@echo "Priority:        Normal" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA)
...</screen>
                                  </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>specifiying releases you<application> don't want</application> run your test for (using "-" sign before given releases): For example, if you don't want to run your test on RHEL3, but the other releases are valid for your test, add "Releases: -RedHatEnterpriseLinux3" to your Makefile METADATA variable, i.e.:  
                                     <screen>
...
@echo "Requires:        openldap-servers" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA)
@echo "Releases:        -RedHatEnterpriseLinux3" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA)
@echo "Priority:        Normal" &gt;&gt; $(METADATA)
...</screen>
                                     </para>
                                  </listitem>
                                </itemizedlist>
                              </para>
                          </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                      </para>
                    </section>
                </section>
