<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Deployment_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Tests-Unassimilated_or_Unfinsihed_Content" lang="en-US">
	<title>Unassimilated or Unfinished content</title>
	 <section id="User_Guide-Getting_Started-Process-Tests-Unassimilated_or_Unfinsihed_Content-Using_the_startup_test_function">
		<title>Using the startup_test function</title>
		 <para>
			The startup_test function can be used to provide a primitive smoketest of a program, by setting a shell variable named result. You will need to use report_result if you use it. The syntax is:
		</para>
		 
<screen>
			startup_test program [arg1] [arg2] [arg3]
</screen>
		 <para>
			The function takes the name of a program, along with up to three arguments. It fakes an X server for the test by ensuring that Xvfb is running (and setting DISPLAY accordingly), then enables core-dumping, and runs the program with the arguments provided, piping standard output and error into OUTPUTFILE (overwriting, not appending).
		</para>
		 <para>
			The function then checks various things: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						any Gtk-CRITICAL warnings found in the resulting OUTPUTFILE cause result to be WARN.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						that the program can be found in the PATH, using the which command; if it is not found it causes result to be FAIL, appending the problem to OUTPUTFILE
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						for binaries, it uses ldd to detect missing libraries; if any are missing it causes result to be FAIL, appending the problems to OUTPUTFILE
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						if any coredumps are detected it causes result to be FAIL
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</para>
		 <para>
			Finally, it kills the fake X server. You then need to report the result.
		</para>
		 
<screen>
            #!/bin/sh
             
            # source the test script helpers
            . /usr/bin/rhts-environment.sh
             
            # ---- do the actual testing ----
            result=PASS 1 
            startup_test /usr/bin/evolution
            report_result $TEST $result 2</screen>
		 <para>
			Normally it's a bad idea to start with a PASS and try to detect a FAIL, since an unexpected error that prevents further setting of the value will lead to a false PASS rather than a false FAIL. Unfortunately in this case the startup_test function requires it.
		</para>
		 
<screen>
		report_result $TEST $result 
</screen>
		 <para>
			We report the result, using the special result shell variable set by startup_test
		</para>

	</section>
	

</section>


